In this video, we're going to be covering
cost of quality.
In an early video, we discussed the five
increasing levels of quality management.
I remember the most expensive approach to
quality management then is the customer,
letting the customer find the defect.
So this is related really to that.
So there's two types then of cost of
quality.
We have the cost of
conformance, and then on the
next slide, we have have
the cost of non-conformance.
It says cost of conformance and cost of
non-conformance.
So let's talk about cost of conformance
first.
And cost of conformance is all the costs
required to build
quality into your product.
Now what's all the cost required for that?
And this is broken up into two further
subcategories.
We have prevention cost and an appraisal
cost.
So a prevention cost, these
are all costs, as the name
suggests, to prevent
issues from occurring, right?
Preventive actions, to try and prevent an
issue from occurring.
So, for example, regular maintenance of
your machines, right, you're trying to
prevent a corrective action, trying to
prevent an issue from occurring.
Using good quality of raw materials,
again, you're trying to prevent a defect,
you're trying to prevent an issue from
occurring, training team members,
sending team member at the right training
at the right time.
Are you trying to prevent human errors?
The whole idea of prevention costs is try
and prevent human errors, system errors,
machine errors, any kind of barriers.
It's trying to prevent an issue from
occurring in the first place.
Documenting procedures, for example,
documenting processes.
So people can follow the procedures and,
you know, reduce potential human error.
also having the right equipment for the
right job.
So, again, reducing wastage and increasing
productivity and so and so forth.
And even just spending the time to do it
right in the first place, rather than
fixing issues afterwards,
we should spend the time
right now to try and prevent
issues from occurring.
I'm sure you can think of a whole bunch of
others.
You know, every industry, every
organization is going to have their own,
ideas of what is a prevention cost or the
whole they're going to come up with their
own procedures regarding preventing issues
from occurring in the first place so the
list is endless these are just some
examples whenever you see this term
appraisal cost an appraisal cost always
refers to testing any kind of testing
you're testing the product testing the
process I think of all the different tests
that you do and your teams do, right, they
all fall under an appraisal cost, right?
So unit testing, regression testing, so
these are just a couple of IT-type testing.
But, you know, there's many, many tests.
So think of all the
different tests that you
do, even things like
destructive testing losses.
You're building the product or you're
testing the product to see if it
withstands a certain amount of force, such
as, for example, crash testing in cars.
I mean, you have to destroy the whole car,
but that is an appraisal cost because you
want to make sure it's conforming to a
particular standard.
Inspecting raw materials before they go
into the machine, right, to make sure that
the right grade and quality, again,
it's an appraisal cost.
So any kind of testing falls under an
appraisal cost.
So these fall under cost of conformance,
right?
You're trying to build quality.
in.
So I want to prevent issues from
occurring, right?
And then we want to test.
Make sure that you're testing the process
as well as testing the product.
Now, the other type
of cost of quality then,
and the next slide is
cost of non-conformance.
And the cost of non-conformance then are
the cost of issues, defects, problems,
failures, and all the costs associated
with that.
And so there's two types.
You have an internal failure cost and an
external failure cost.
An internal, failure cost, costs
associated with the non-conformance of
products or issues with the process during
the project.
That's an internal fairly cost,
such as, for example, you're testing a
product, it's not doing what it's supposed
to be doing, right?
It's a defect.
We have to fix it.
So, rework, defect repair, rework,
that's a internal failure cost.
It's not doing what it's supposed to,
we do.
Or we have to get rid of it all together.
Scrap.
Or even downtime, unplanned downtime.
Machine suddenly crashes.
No one can do any work.
So now we need to fix that machine.
That's going to cost.
And then plus the unplanned downtime.
All of that would be an internal failure
cost.
Internal failure costs can also be things
like low team morale.
Team members are not enjoying what they're
doing right there's low morale in in the
team right so that would be an internal
failure cost and again i'm sure i can
think of a whole bunch of others but an
internal failure cost specifically refers
to while we are working on the project any
failures that we're seeing during the
project that would be an internal failure
cost and an external failure cost is once
the product has reached the customer and
now the customer is finding problems that
now is an external failure cost and all
the costs associated with that such as as
it says here liability warranty work
litigation claims loss of reputation loss
of business recalls these would all be an
external fairly cost because now the
customer has found the problem the
customer is finding this year and remember
that is the highest cost of quality by
letting the customer find it now be
careful with internal and external failure
cost, right?
An external failure cost is once a product
has been delivered to the customer,
right?
Sometimes, well, or rather in a lot of
projects, before a product is officially
delivered to the customer, the customer is
going to test the product, right?
Sometimes they call it user acceptance
testing.
At that point, if they've found issues.
At that point, that would
still be considered an
internal failure cost because
the project is not closed.
The project is still open.
It's just that the customer is now doing
their testing.
So we've built the product, we meaning our
team, we've built the product.
And now we've tested the product as part
of call to control.
We as a team, we've tested the product.
now we've given it to the customer for
their sign-off, right, for their acceptance.
So now the customer is going to be
testing.
If they find any issues at
that point, then it's still an
internal failure cost because
the project is still open.
Once the project is closed and now,
once we deliver the final product to the
customer, and now the finding problems,
now the finding issues, at that point,
that would be an extra.
external failure cost, which is the
highest cost of quality.
So these are the two major headings then
of cost of quality.
You have cost of conformance, cost of
non-conformance.
In the cost of conformance, you have
prevention costs, appraisal cost,
cost of non-conformance, internal failure
cost and an external failure cost.